//=====ANIMATION INITIALIZATION=====AOS.init({duration: 800,once: true});//=====QUIZ DATA=====const quizData=[{question: "What is the most important thing to check before traveling with your pet by air?",options: ["Airline pet policies","Pet food prices","Hotel availability","Weather forecast"],correct: "A",explanation: "Always check airline pet policies first,as requirements vary greatly between airlines and can include breed restrictions,carrier size limits,and seasonal travel bans."},{question: "When traveling by car,pets should NEVER be allowed to:",options: ["Sit on your lap","Ride with head out window","Wear a seatbelt harness","Have access to water"],correct: "B",options: ["Sit on your lap","Ride with head out window","Wear a seatbelt harness","Have access to water"],correct: "B",explanation: "Pets should never ride with their head out the window due to wind,debris,and the risk of injury from sudden stops or accidents."},{question: "What type of carrier is required for most airline pet travel?",options: ["Soft-sided bag","Cardboard box","IATA-approved hard-sided carrier","Plastic storage bin"],correct: "C",explanation: "Most airlines require IATA-approved hard-sided carriers that meet specific size,ventilation,and safety standards for pet travel."},{question: "Before traveling,you should schedule a veterinary check-up at least:",options: ["Same day","1 week before","2-4 weeks before","6 months before"],correct: "C",explanation: "Schedule a vet check-up 2-4 weeks before travel to ensure vaccinations are current,address any health issues,and get travel medications if needed."},{question: "When choosing a pet-friendly hotel,you should ask about:",options: ["Room service menu","Pet fees and restrictions","Spa services","Restaurant hours"],correct: "B",explanation: "Always inquire about pet policies,fees,breed restrictions,and any additional rules before booking a pet-friendly accommodation."},{question: "For international pet travel,which document is typically required?",options: ["Pet's birth certificate","Health certificate from a veterinarian","Pet's social media following","Owner's credit score"],correct: "B",explanation: "International travel usually requires a health certificate from a licensed veterinarian,issued within a specific timeframe before travel."},{question: "What should you do if your pet shows signs of stress during travel?",options: ["Ignore it until it stops","Yell to get their attention","Take breaks and comfort them","Feed them more food"],correct: "C",explanation: "If your pet shows stress,take frequent breaks,offer comfort,ensure they have water,and consider consulting your vet about calming aids."},{question: "When camping with pets,you should:",options: ["Let them roam freely","Keep them leashed at all times","Leave them in the car","Feed them human food"],correct: "B",explanation: "Always keep pets leashed in campgrounds to protect them from wildlife,prevent them from wandering,and comply with campground rules."},{question: "For boat travel,pets should wear:",options: ["Sunglasses","Life jackets designed for pets","Winter coats","Fashion accessories"],correct: "B",explanation: "Pet life jackets are essential for boat safety,providing buoyancy and helping pets stay afloat if they fall overboard."},{question: "What is the safest way to transport a pet in a car?",options: ["Loose in the back seat","In a secure carrier or crate","Standing on the console","In the cargo area without restraint"],correct: "B",explanation: "Pets should be secured in a carrier,crate,or with a pet seatbelt harness to prevent injury during sudden stops,turns,or accidents."}];//=====QUIZ STATE=====let currentQuestionIndex=0;let score=0;let selectedAnswer=null;//=====DOM ELEMENTS=====const questionText=document.getElementById('questionText');const options=document.querySelectorAll('.option');const nextBtn=document.getElementById('nextBtn');const prevBtn=document.getElementById('prevBtn');const progressFill=document.getElementById('progressFill');const currentQuestionSpan=document.getElementById('currentQuestion');const feedbackSection=document.getElementById('feedbackSection');const feedbackTitle=document.getElementById('feedbackTitle');const feedbackText=document.getElementById('feedbackText');const resultsSection=document.getElementById('resultsSection');const finalScore=document.getElementById('finalScore');const scoreMessage=document.getElementById('scoreMessage');//=====QUIZ FUNCTIONS=====function loadQuestion(){const currentQuestion=quizData[currentQuestionIndex];questionText.textContent=currentQuestion.question;options.forEach((option,index)=>{const optionLetter=String.fromCharCode(65+index);// A,B,C,D option.querySelector('.option-text').textContent=currentQuestion.options[index];option.className='option';// Reset classes option.style.pointerEvents='auto';// Re-enable clicking});selectedAnswer=null;feedbackSection.style.display='none';updateProgress();updateNavigation();}function updateProgress(){const progress=((currentQuestionIndex+1)/ quizData.length)* 100;progressFill.style.width=`${progress}%`;currentQuestionSpan.textContent=currentQuestionIndex+1;}function updateNavigation(){prevBtn.style.display=currentQuestionIndex > 0 ? 'block' : 'none';nextBtn.textContent=currentQuestionIndex===quizData.length-1 ? 'Finish' : 'Next';}function selectOption(optionElement){if(selectedAnswer)return;// Prevent multiple selections selectedAnswer=optionElement.dataset.option;options.forEach(option=> option.classList.remove('selected'));optionElement.classList.add('selected');checkAnswer();}function checkAnswer(){const currentQuestion=quizData[currentQuestionIndex];const isCorrect=selectedAnswer===currentQuestion.correct;if(isCorrect){score++;feedbackTitle.textContent='Correct! ðŸŽ‰';feedbackTitle.style.color='#2A9D8F';}else{feedbackTitle.textContent='Not quite right ðŸ˜…';feedbackTitle.style.color='#E76F51';}feedbackText.textContent=currentQuestion.explanation;feedbackSection.style.display='block';// Highlight correct and incorrect answers options.forEach(option=>{const optionLetter=option.dataset.option;if(optionLetter===currentQuestion.correct){option.classList.add('correct');}else if(optionLetter===selectedAnswer && !isCorrect){option.classList.add('incorrect');}option.style.pointerEvents='none';// Disable further clicking});}function nextQuestion(){if(currentQuestionIndex < quizData.length-1){currentQuestionIndex++;loadQuestion();}else{showResults();}}function previousQuestion(){if(currentQuestionIndex > 0){currentQuestionIndex--;loadQuestion();}}function showResults(){document.querySelector('.quiz-card').style.display='none';resultsSection.style.display='block';finalScore.textContent=score;let message='';if(score >=9){message='Excellent! You\'re a pet travel expert! ðŸ†';}else if(score >=7){message='Great job! You know your pet travel tips well! ðŸŒŸ';}else if(score >=5){message='Good effort! Keep learning about pet travel safety! ðŸ“š';}else{message='Keep studying pet travel tips-safety first! ðŸŽ“';}scoreMessage.textContent=message;}function restartQuiz(){currentQuestionIndex=0;score=0;selectedAnswer=null;document.querySelector('.quiz-card').style.display='block';resultsSection.style.display='none';loadQuestion();}function shareOnWhatsApp(){const text=`I scored ${score}/10 on the Pet Travel Tips Quiz! ðŸ•âœˆï¸ Test your knowledge: ${window.location.href}`;const whatsappUrl=`https://wa.me/?text=${encodeURIComponent(text)}`;window.open(whatsappUrl,'_blank');}//=====EVENT LISTENERS=====options.forEach(option=>{option.addEventListener('click',()=> selectOption(option));});nextBtn.addEventListener('click',nextQuestion);prevBtn.addEventListener('click',previousQuestion);//=====INITIALIZE QUIZ=====document.addEventListener('DOMContentLoaded',loadQuestion);